Inventory of the Thomas Byrne Edsall papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Farmers, undated (Box-folder 39: 1)
- Government investment, 1986-1990 (Box-folder 39: 2)
- Health care, 1990 (Box-folder 39: 3)
- Housing, 1984-1990 (Box-folder 39: 4)
  Includes clippings, printed matter, data sheets, and report
- Election, 1984 (Box-folder 39: 5)
  Magazine
- Jobs II, 1986-1990 (Box-folder 39: 6-8)
  Includes charts, clippings, printed matter, conference paper, data sheets, letter to the editor, and schedule
- Jobs III, 1987-1990 (Box-folder 39: 9)
  Article, conference paper, and datasheets
- Inflation, 1984 (Box-folder 39: 10)
- "Ronald Reagan-—Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) Informant," San Jose Mercury News, Scott Herhold (with Jack Sirica), 1985 August 25 (Box-folder 39: 11)
- Ronald Reagan/Blacks, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 39: 12)
- Income, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 40: 1-3)
  Includes clippings, printed matter, data sheets, paper, press release, remarks, report, and statement
- Ronald Reagan, 1976-1989 (Box-folder 40: 4)
  Includes clippings, printed matter, and reports
- Ronald Reagan, 1980-1986 (Box-folder 40: 5)
  Clippings, printed matter, and reports
- Race nexus, 1986-1990 (Box-folder 40: 6-7)
  Includes articles, clippings, printed matter, conference papers, essays, and magazines. Also includes an empty folder titled, "Lawrence Bobo: Center for Advanced Study"
- Global race conflict, 1990 (Box-folder 41: 1)
- Fred Siegel, 1987-1990 (Box-folder 41: 2)
  Articles by Fred Siegel, correspondence with Thomas and Mary Edsall, and clippings, and printed matter
- Social Security, 1990 (Box-folder 41: 3)
- David A. Stockman, 1986 (Box-folder 41: 4)
  Includes clippings, magazine containing excerpts from Stockman's book, The Triumph of Politics, press release, and typescript reviews of Stockman's books by Thomas Edsall. Also includes a print depicting David Stockman
- Think tanks, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 41: 5)
  Clippings and reports
- Two-tier economy, 1987 (Box-folder 41: 6)
- Television in politics, 1977-1985 (Box-folder 41: 7-8)
  Includes article, market opinion research survey, media kit, and study
- Articles, clippings, and papers by others, 1985-1991
- Outlook/Christian, 1985 June (Box-folder 42: 1)
  (folder empty)
- Prize file, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 42: 2)
  Includes 2 photocopies of articles by Thomas Edsall-—"Racetracks, Banks, and Liquor Stores," Washington Monthly; and "Money and Morality in Maryland," Society; and printed copy of "Maryland," The New Republic
- Clippings and printed matter, 1987-1989
- Interview with Paul Weyrich, 1984 (Box-folder 42: 3)
- Clipping-—International, 1987 (Box-folder 42: 4)
- Douglas Wilder-—Clippings and printed matter, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 42: 5)
  Includes handwritten notes, undated
- Voting rights, 1982-1990
  - Clippings, U.S. Department of Justice correspondence with different individuals, appeals to the U.S. Department of Justice regarding the changes in the Democratic party rules in Alabama in violation of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 and response of the state Democratic Party (Box-folder 42: 6)
  - "Analysis of Racial Distinction in Voter Registration Rates, State of Mississippi," Allan J. Lichtman, undated, and report, "Voting Rights Act of 1965 as Amended," Paul M. Downing, 1984 (Box-folder 42: 7)
- Democrats-—Incumbency, 1988 (Box-folder 42: 8)
  Clippings and report on partisan distribution of Political Action Committee (PAC) contributions and a cover letter from Dick Cheney
- Phyllis Schlafly-–Report and clippings, 1982-1986 (Box-folder 42: 9)
- William Schneider, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 42: 10)
  Articles in Atlantic and New Republic. Includes a 5.25-inch computer disk containing piece on "Reagan Legacy"
- GOP
  - Voter registration, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 42: 11)
  - Economy, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 42: 12)
  - Defense, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 42: 13)
- Winners and losers, 1988 (Box-folder 42: 14)
- Working poor, 1989 (Box-folder 42: 15)
- Jim Wright, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 42: 16)
  Clippings about Jim Wright and a typescript article by Thomas Edsall focusing on ethics investigation
- Republican-—Local parties, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 42: 17)
- Republican Party, 1983-1986
  - State and National Committee members' names (Box-folder 42: 18)
  - Interpretive pieces. (Box-folder 42: 19)
- Reapportionment, 1992 (Box-folder 42: 20-21)
  Includes articles, clippings, list of legislators' names, and summary
- "Second thoughts About Race in America," conference, Washington, D.C., 1990 May 3 (Box-folder 43: 1)
  Includes attendance, participants' lists, related articles, and newsletters
- Redistricting and voting rights, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 43: 2-3)
  Includes articles, conference papers, and clippings
- Reform-—Unintended consequences, 1989 (Box-folder 43: 4)
- Regulation, 1984-1990 (Box-folder 43: 5)
- Robert Teeter, undated (Box-folder 43: 6)
  Foreword to a survey. Typescript fragment
- Schools, 1990 (Box-folder 43: 7)
- Second quintile, 1986 (Box-folder 43: 8)
- Voter turnout, 1980-1989 (Box-folder 43: 9)
  Articles, clippings, press release, and turnout statistics
- Voter registration, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 43: 10)
  Articles and clippings
- Reviews of Jim Sleeper, Closest of Strangers: Liberalism and the Politics of Race in New York, by Anthony Lukas, New York Times Book Review, and by Salim Muwakkil, Currents, 1990 (Box-folder 43: 11)
- Harold Meyerson, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 43: 12)
  Articles with a cover letter to Thomas Edsall, and clipping
- Jefferson Morley, undated (Box-folder 43: 13)
  Letter from Thomas Edsall
- Kay Moseley, 1988? (Box-folder 43: 14)
- Michael A. Newman, 1986 (Box-folder 43: 15)
  Medical report
- Sam Nunn, 1988 (Box-folder 43: 16)
  Campaign speech for Michael Dukakis. Typescript
- Rat eradication bill, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 43: 17)
- Tikkun, 1987 (Box-folder 43: 18)
  Letter from Nan Fink to Thomas Edsall and a form letter
- Leigh Jackson, 1990 (Box-folder 43: 19)
  Copies of articles by Jackson and his letter to Thomas Edsall
- Review of Mickey Kaus's articles, New Republic, 1986, and Kaus's article in the Washington Post, 1990 (Box-folder 43: 20)
- Thomas Edsall--Article, 1990 July 9 (Box-folder 44: 1)
- Bill Peterson, 1990 (Box-folder 44: 2)
  Obituary, program for burial service, letter from Mary Edsall to Linda Peterson, and typescript diary
- Retirement, 1990 (Box-folder 44: 3)
- Merrill Shanks (Box-folder 44: 4)
- Swarthmore College, 1987 (Box-folder 44: 5)
  Typescript notes on Bob Edgar's speech and his letter of invitation to Thomas Edsall to speak at the college about his book, The New Politics of Inequality
- Untitled, 1990 (Box-folder 44: 6)
  Memorandum from Jennifer Widner regarding summary of ideas generated at October 10, 1990, workshop on "Improving the Learning Environment for Women"
- Television materials for Thomas Edsall, 1986 (Box-folder 44: 7)
  Includes C-Span notes, CBS notes, and program from Nightline, ABC News
- Income II, 1989 (Box-folder 44: 8)
  "Money Income of Households, Families, and Persons in the United States: 1987," current population report, U.S. Department of Commerce, 1989
- Japan-—Mary Edsall, 1992 (Box-folder 44: 9)
  Includes itinerary and program details from United States Information Agency (USIA) for Mary's upcoming visit to Japan; typescript draft of Mary's speech in Japan; and communication between USIA and embassy in Tokyo
- Ronald Steel, 1958-1990 (Box-folder 44: 10-11)
  Includes clippings, printed matter, membership report of United Steelworkers of America, and list of shutdowns of steel plants and production facilities
- Tom Stiles, 1989 (Box-folder 44: 12)
- Clippings on changing neighborhood by Thomas Edsall, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 44: 13)
- Correspondence regarding Nieman Fellowship, Nieman Foundation, 1971-1973, and Thomas Edsall's letter to Newspaper Guild regarding Heywood Broun Award contest (Folder 44)
- "Policy Direction and Performance Evaluation: Complementary Explanations of the Reagan Elections," J. Merrill Shanks and Warren E. Miller, paper to be presented at the Annual Meeting of the American Political Science Association, New Orleans, Louisiana, 1985 September 1 (Folder 44)
- Clippings, 1972-1989 (Box 45)
- Clippings (Box 46)
  - 1969 (Box-folder 46: 1)
    Envelope labeled the Sun
  - 1972-1988 (Folder 46)
  - 1974-1979 (Box-folder 46: 2)
  - 1980-1984 (Box-folder 46: 3)
  - 1984 (Box-folder 46: 4)
    Includes a copy of Management, UCLA Graduate School of Management
  - 1985-1986 (Folder 46)
- Thomas Edsall-—Clippings, 1977 (Box-folder 46: 5)
- Outlook, 1985 (Box-folder 46: 6)
  Includes typescript and photocopy of some articles by Thomas Edsall
- Photocopies of printed articles, 1980-1986 (Folder 46)
- "Party Politics: Money Changes Everything," political analysis from "Money (and Politics) in Both Parties," by Thomas Edsall, Harper's Magazine, 1986 December (Box-folder 47: 1)
- Thomas Edsall's file, 1978 June (Box-folder 47: 2)
  Empty envelope with some handwritten notes
- Thomas Edsall's clips-— Washington Post, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 47: 3)
  Includes two printed copies of an article from the Sun, undated
- Article on George Bush's outlook by Thomas Edsall, 1986 (Box-folder 47: 4)
- Clippings, 1972-1989
- Thomas Edsall-—Clippings, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 48: 1)
  The folder is incorrectly dated as 1976
- "Equality," New Republic, 1986 (Box-folder 48: 2)
  Includes clippings and printed matter, 1980
- Clippings, 1977-1989 (Box-folder 48: 3)
- Writings by Thomas Edsall. (Folder 48)
  - "Mikulski Went to Washington and Surprised Everybody,", 1971? September 18 (Folder 48)
  - "Good Connections: Luring Clients: Ex-Aides Capitalize on White House Work,", 1985 October 27 (Folder 48)
  - "Hopefuls Look Right for Support: Abortion Is Key Issue as GOP 1988 Contenders Woo Conservatives,", 1986 January 21 (Folder 48)
  - "Republicans See Signs of '86 Majority: Survey Trends, Economy Give Encouragement for Off-Year Races,", 1986 January 25 (Folder 48)
- Clippings, circa 1971-1989 (Box 49)
- Alabama (Box-folder 50: 1-2)
  (folders empty)
- Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD), 1989 (Box-folder 50: 3)
  Statistics on member countries
- Barthelemy, 1986 (Box-folder 50: 4)
- Speeches and writings by others, 1981-1989 (Box 50)
- Memorandum regarding southern polls, 1988 July 5 (Box 50)
- Report on state finances, 1989 (Box 50)
- Summons in civil action, United States District Court, 1985 (Box 50)
- Statement of organization--Reports of itemized receipts and disbursements, 1986? (Box 50)
- Henson Election Committee--List of itemized disbursements, 1986 (Box 50)
- "Alabama's Democratic Agenda: Making 1989 the 'Year of the White Male,'" by Thomas Edsall, undated (Box 50)
- Radio Shack 200 Manual, 1986 (Box 50)
- Clippings and printed matter, 1986-1989 (Box 50)
- Miscellany, 1989 (Box 50)
- 16 mini sound cassettes--Nashville, Citadel, Columbia, and Louisiana, 1986 (Box-folder 51: 1)
- 4 mini sound cassettes. One - Robert Teeter, 1985, rest unidentified (Box-folder 51: 2)
- Mini sound cassettes (Box 51)
  - 16 cassettes, mostly undated and unlabeled. (Box 51)
    Includes labels: Robertson, New Orleans, Henry Brandon, and Sherman Copelin?
  - 2 cassettes, 1985, including 1--GOP (Box 51)
  - 1 cassette, 1986—Nashville (Box 51)
- Compact sound cassettes (Box 51)
  - 13 cassettes, undated and mostly unlabeled or unclear labels (Box 51)
  - 1 cassette, 1983 December 27--Roger Allen Moore (Box 51)
  - 2 cassettes, 1984--Daniels and Franks (Box 51)
  - 1 cassette, 1986--JW/talk (Box 51)
  - 8 cassettes, 1989 (Box 51)
    - Birmingham--5 cassettes (Box 51)
    - Ed Rollins--1 cassette (Box 51)
    - Joe Rodgers--1 cassette (Box 51)
    - Affirmative Action--talk shows (Box 51)
  - 1 cassette, 1998? (Box 51)
    John Lewis?
- "Who's Who?" Letters to Thomas Edsall, 1989 (Box-folder 52: 1)
- Notes from Judy Nichol and notebooks, undated (Box 52)
- Letters from Bill Domhoff, Chandler Davidson, Dave Denson, Gary Gerstle, Gregg Ivers, and James Warren, 1990 (Box 52)
- James Stimson, Public Opinion in America: Moods, Cycles, and Swings, to be reviewed by Thomas Edsall. Includes a letter from Rachel Quenk, 1991 May 17 (Box 52)
  Galley proof
- Review of Christopher Jenks, Rethinking Social Policy: Race, Poverty, and the Underclass, undated (Box 52)
- Washington Post, 1984 June - 1988 July 25-31 (Box 52)
- Clips regarding Chain Reaction, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 53: 1)
- Letters of appreciation and thanks, 1991-1993 (Box 53)
- Clippings and printed matter, 1991-1992 (Box 53)
- Writings by others, 1991 (Box 53)
- National Colloquium VIII, remarks, undated (Box 53)
- Review of Thomas (with Mary) Edsall, Chain Reaction, New York Times Book Review, 1991 October 20 (Box 53)
- Contribution, script for the corporate advertising audiovisual slide presentation, 1992 March 11 (Box 53)
- Letters to Thomas and Mary Edsall, 1991-1992, and a typescript copy of Norman Birnbaum's opening speech, Friederich-Ebert Foundation Conference, Washington, D.C., 1991 September 12 (Box 53)
- Miscellany, 1992 (Box 53)
- 2 photographic prints depicting unidentified individuals, undated and 1991 (Box-folder 54: 1)
- Letters to Thomas and Mary Edsall relating to Thomas Edsall's speaking engagements, evaluations of his speeches and writings, reviews and comments by him of writings by others, 1989-1992, and conference brochures, 1991-1994 (Box 54)
- Clippings, printed matter, and miscellany, 1991-1993 (Box 54)
- Chain Reaction-—Mail and stories, 1970 (Box-folder 55: 1)
- Clippings, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 55: 2)
  Includes articles by Thomas Edsall
- Articles by Thomas Edsall.
  - 1969 (Box-folder 55: 3)
  - 1974 (Box-folder 55: 4)
- Clippings, 1970-1971 (Box 55)
- New York Review of Books, 1992-1993 (Box 55)
- Photocopies of articles by Thomas Edsall and clippings for future use, 1965-1971 (Box-folder 56: 1)
- Articles by Thomas Edsall, 1970 (Box-folder 56: 2-3)
  Clippings. Includes letters to him
- Clippings and printed matter, 1970-1976 (Box-folder 56: 4-7)
- "Mandel Magic," Thomas Edsall, Perspective, 1973 April (Box-folder 57: 1)
- Review of Thomas Edsall, The Left Languishes: The New Politics of Inequality (Box-folder 57: 2)
  - Washington Journalism Review, undated (Box 57)
    printed copy
  - Jack Kisling, Denver Post, 1985 November 3 (Box 57)
    Clipping and printed copy
  - Wilson Quarterly, 1985 winter (Box 57)
- Copies of New York Review of Books, 1985 February 28 (Box-folder 57: 3)
- Clippings and article by Michael Harrington, The Progressive, 1985 March (Box 57)
- Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 57)
- List of names, undated (Box 57)
- Thomas Edsall, The Left Languishes: The New Politics of Inequality (Box 57)
  - Brochures, undated (Box 57)
  - Comments, Book News, 1984 June 25 (Box 57)
- Reviews (Box 57)
  - Robert Kuttner, New Republic, 1984 October 29 (Box 57)
  - Murray Kempton, New York Review of Books, 1985 February 28 (Box 57)
  - Robert Dunn, Mother Jones, 1985 February – March (Box 57)
- Washington Post, 1989 (Box 57)
- Clippings and printed matter, 1972-1989 (Box 57)
- Articles by Thomas Edsall, Washington Post, 1984 (Box-folder 58: 1)
- Clippings and printed matter, 1984 (Box-folder 58: 2)
  Folder title indicates photographs, but none found
- Articles and letters, 1984 (Box-folder 58: 3)
- The New Politics of Inequality--Reviews, 1984 (Box-folder 58: 4-5)
  Clippings and printed copy
- Clippings, printed matter, and photocopies of articles, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 58: 6)
- Chain Reaction (Box 59)
  - Typescript chapters, 1990 (Box-folder 59: 1-3)
  - Bibliography, review, letters, clippings, and notes, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 59: 4)
  - Published volume, 1991 (Box 59)
- Handwritten notes, undated (Box-folder 59: 5)
- Chain Reaction (Box 60)
  - Notes, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 60: 1)
  - Typescript chapters, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 60: 2-3)
- Articles and reviews by Thomas Edsall, 1991 (Box-folder 60: 4-5)
- Important list of book points and notes, 1990 (Box-folder 60: 6)
- GOP book, 1983-1989 (Box-folder 60: 7-9)
  Includes book ideas, 1985-1988
- Race book-—Important notes, ideas, and memoranda, 1988 (Box-folder 60: 10)
- Correspondence with Donald S. Lamm, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 60: 11)
  Includes typescript outline for politics and race book, 1988
- "Party Development and Decline," outline of remarks for panel discussion, undated (Box 60)
- Articles and reviews by Thomas Edsall, 1991 (Box 60)
- Miscellany, 1990-1991 (Box 60)
- Thomas Edsall-—Best clippings, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 61: 1)
- Clippings and printed matter, 1970-1988 (Box-folder 61: 2)
- Early version, chapter one-—Race book, 1990 August – September (Box-folder 61: 3)
- Articles, New York Review proofs, 1992 (Box-folder 61: 4)
  Typescript. Includes galley proofs and letters
- 11 5.25-inch computer disks for chapters not updated (GOP book)?, 1990 July 18 (Box-folder 61: 5)
- "City Hall: Inside Dope," Baltimore Advocate, 1970 September 1 (Box-folder 61: 6)
  Printed copy. Includes typescript index for Chain Reaction and a cover letter to Thomas Edsall, 1991 June 26
- Clippings, 1971 (Box 61)
- "Maryland: The Governor Raiseth," Washington Monthly, 1972 February (Box-folder 62: 1)
  Photocopy of an article by Thomas Edsall
- Clippings, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 62: 2-5)
- "Liberalism Is Out of Style: Neighborhood Issues Stressed," 1970 August? Photocopy of an article by Thomas Edsall. Also includes application, 1971 February 28, and personal statements, undated, for Lucius W. Nieman Fellowships for Newspapermen, Harvard University; letter of reference for Thomas Edsall, 1971 March 12; and a letter of acknowledgement from Tenney K. Lehman (Box-folder 62: 6)
- Clippings, 1970 August – October (Box-folder 62: 7)
- Articles.
  - "The Meritocracy Scare" (with Karl W. Deutsch), Society, 1972 September – October (Box-folder 62: 8)
  - "I.Q.: Measurement of Race and Class?" Society, 1973 May – June, R. J. Herrnstein's response to the criticism of his article, "I.Q.", Atlantic Magazine, 1971 September, by Thomas Edsall and Karl W. Deutsch in "The Meritocracy Scare," Society, 1972 September - October (Box 62)
  - Comments about Thomas Edsall, "Baltimore on a String," Joan Seidman, Baltimore Magazine, 1974 March (Box 62)
  - "State Politics and Public Interests: Money and Mortality in Maryland," Society, 1974 May - June (Box 62)
- Clippings, 1972-1988 (Box 62)
  Includes article by Thomas Edsall
- 1 photographic print depicting the senators from Maryland, 1971 March (Box 62)
- Advertisements for awards in different categories of newspaper writing and editing, Editor and Publisher, 1976 January, and Thomas Edsall's letters regarding his submission for the awards, 1976 January 30 (Box-folder 63: 1)
  Includes acknowledgement for a Pulitzer Prize in Journalism, Columbia University, New York, 1976 February 3
- Correspondence
  - Thomas O'Neil series, 1978 (Box-folder 63: 2)
    Also includes clippings
  - W. Shepherdson Abell, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 63: 3)
  - Boston University, 1979 (Box-folder 63: 4)
    Letters from Thomas Edsall
  - Henry J. Hyde, 1979 (Box-folder 63: 5)
- 1980 election-—Political beat, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 63: 6)
  Typescript notes and memorandum
- Post Senate series, 1975 February (Box-folder 63: 7)
- Typescript fragments for a novel, undated (Box-folder 63: 8)
- Strike list, 1973 June (Box-folder 63: 9)
- "America Needs an Establishment," Peter Schrag, Harper's, 1975 December (Box-folder 63: 10)
- Article about Jackson Thomas Stephens, Sun, 1978 May 15 (Box-folder 63: 11)
  Clippings and typescript
- Black chapter, undated (Box-folder 63: 12)
- Poker--List of names and telephone numbers, 1981 (Box-folder 63: 13-14)
- Outline material for a book, undated (Box-folder 63: 15)
- "The Battle of the Budget," The Nation, 1980 May 10 (Box-folder 63: 16)
- Stuff of the members of the House of Representatives, United States Congress. (Box-folder 63: 17)
  Includes clipping, 1979; typescript notes on leadership, undated; letter from Morris K. Udall, undated; and a memorandum from John Brademas, 1979 November 8
- Face the Nation, 1981 April 12 (Box-folder 63: 18)
  Typescript notes and a letter from Barry William Messinger, 1981 April 14
- Campaign 1980--Articles by Thomas Edsall (Box-folder 63: 19)
  Clippings and photocopy of a printed article
- Standing Committee of Correspondents, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 63: 20)
  Clippings and lists of contestants for memberships and voters
- Weapons series (Box-folder 63: 21)
- Campaign 1980-—Articles by Thomas Edsall (Box-folder 63: 22)
- Article about James Jones, Sun, 1981 April 27 (Box-folder 63: 23)
- Squash members-—List of members, 1975-1978, and related materials (Box-folder 63: 24)
- Article, Washington Monthly, photocopy of an article, Stan Isaacs, Newsday, and Afterdark, 1974-1981 (Box-folder 63: 25)
- Thomas Edsall--Clippings, Washington Tribune, and other clippings, Washington, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 63: 26)
- Letters regarding book? Dissent, 1984 February (Box-folder 63: 27)
  The folder is incorrectly labeled as 1984 March
- IBM PC users' group, 1983 (Box-folder 63: 28)
- Washington Star, 1981 (Box-folder 63: 29)
- Series of three articles on business, Sun, undated (Box 63)
- Printed fragment of an article by Thomas Edsall? The New Yorker, 1974 February 4 (Box 63)
- Stephen Graae-—Clipping, undated (Box-folder 64: 1)
- Haynes Johnson-—Note, 1984 July 13 (Box-folder 64: 2)
- Demographs, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 64: 3)
- Information on public financing, 1978 (Box-folder 64: 4)
  Includes clippings, 1980-1981
- Hal? letter, typescript articles by others, 1981, and clippings, 1983 (Box-folder 64: 5)
- Dick book? Note only, undated (Box-folder 64: 6)
- Bob Healy—-1 compact sound cassette, 1981 September 9, and handwritten notes, undated (Box-folder 64: 7)
- Mailing list, undated (Box-folder 64: 8)
- Announcement of the publication of a new journal, Journal of Social Reconstruction, undated (Box-folder 64: 9)
- Clippings, 1977 (Box-folder 64: 10)
- Memorabilia-—Ronald Reagan, 1981 (Box-folder 64: 11)
  Includes reproductions of the photographs of Ronald Reagan and George Herbert Walker Bush, invitation to the inauguration ceremonies, program, and floor plan of the United States Capitol grounds
- Contract to appear on the program, Face the Nation, as a panelist, Washington, D.C., 1981 April 12 (Box-folder 64: 12)
- Manuscript reader-—Note and a letter, 1983 August 25 (Box-folder 64: 13)
- Thomas Edsall's letters to the Internal Revenue Service, 1983 August 1 (Box-folder 64: 14)
  Includes a receipt for certified mail
- Letter from Frank Swoboda to the Scripps-Howard Foundation nominating Thomas Edsall for a Roy W. Howard Award, 1983 February 14 (Box-folder 64: 15)
- Letter from Ernest B. Furgurson to The Amos Tuck School of Business Administration, Dartmouth College, Hanover, New Hampshire, 1981 January 15, regarding entry of Thomas Edsall's article, "Business Learns to Play New Politics" (Box-folder 64: 16-17)
- Prize file, 1983-—Assessment of Thomas Edsall's work as a journalist and letters from Frank Swoboda to different organizations and academic institutions recommending Thomas Edsall for awards. (Box-folder 64: 18)
- Outline for a book by Thomas Edsall focusing on recent trends in federal tax policy and the impact of political forces on them, 1983 (Box-folder 64: 19)
- Jim Rousmanier?, 1985 (Box-folder 64: 20)
  Letter to Thomas and Mary Edsall
- Evening Sun-—Reunion, 75th anniversary, 1985 (Box-folder 64: 21)
  Includes brochure, printed matter, and program
- Review of Xandra Kayden and Eddie Mahe Jr., The Party Goes On: The Persistence of the Two-Party System in the United States, 1986 (Box-folder 64: 22)
  Typescript. Includes tables and empty envelopes
- Kevin Brown, undated (Box-folder 64: 23)
- Tyler Bridges, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 64: 24)
  Letters neither from nor to Thomas Edsall
- Maurice Zeitlin, 1986 (Box-folder 64: 25)
- Ernest J. Oakleaf, 1986 (Box-folder 64: 26)
- David Broder, undated (Box-folder 64: 27)